cognex.com 2019-12-23

# Privacy Policy | Cognex

LEGAL INFORMATION: Cognex Corporation

**© Copyright - 2019. Cognex Corporation. All Rights Reserved.**

### GENERAL PRIVACY POLICY

The contents of this web site, including but not limited to all text, designs and images appearing herein (collectively, the "Contents"), are copyrighted works owned by Cognex Corporation ("Cognex" or the "Company"). Any copying, reproduction, modification, distribution or other unauthorized use of the Contents, including any portion or version thereof, is prohibited. Notwithstanding the foregoing, users of this web site have the limited permission to view, copy, print and distribute the Contents for non-commercial, informational purposes so long as any copy or other reproduction includes the above copyright notice.

The products, processes, technology and related information described in this web site may be covered by one or more issued or pending Cognex patents. No license or other intellectual property right to such Cognex products, processes or technologies is granted or conferred by this web site or by anything appearing herein.

The trademarks and registered trademarks of Cognex referenced or used in this web site appear as marked and may not be used for any purpose without the express written permission of Cognex. All other brand names, designs, service marks and trademarks (whether or not registered) referenced or used herein are the property of their respective owners. Any reference to or use of third-party trademarks in this web site shall not constitute and is not intended to indicate such third party's affiliation with or endorsement of Cognex products and services.

The product and/or service information set forth in this web site may be outdated, may contain errors and omissions, and is subject to change without notice. No statement, representation or other information contained in this web site should be construed as binding upon Cognex contractually or otherwise the basis for any express or implied warranty. Please contact the Company during normal business hours for the most up-to-date information regarding specific products and services.

This web site may provide users with access (whether by hypertext links, framing or otherwise as applicable) to certain other non-Cognex web sites. Any such access is provided with the understanding that the contents of non-Cognex sites are beyond the control of Cognex, that Cognex makes no representations whatsoever about such sites, and that users shall proceed at their own risk.

Certain matters discussed in this web site may constitute "forward-looking statements" within the meaning of the federal securities laws. The Company's results may differ materially from the expectations, estimates or projections contained in the forward-looking statements as a result of certain risk factors, as listed and discussed in the Company's registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Cognex disclaims any obligation subsequently to revise forward-looking statements to reflect events or circumstances after the date of such statements or to reflect the occurrence of anticipated or unanticipated events. The reader should not place undue reliance upon any forward-looking statements.

**Privacy Statement for Cognex Web Site**  

We at Cognex respect your privacy and recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information you share with us (any information by which you can be identified, such as name, address, and telephone number). That is why Cognex has established this privacy policy – so that you can understand the care with which we will treat your information.

In general, you may visit [www.cognex.com](https://www.cognex.com/) without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. However, at times, we may request that you share personal information with us in order to obtain access to certain features of our site or to request additional information from us. If you choose to provide personal information, we assure you that we will take appropriate steps to protect the information you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still visit most of our web site, but you may be unable to access certain areas, options, or services.

Cognex will use your information to better understand your needs for machine vision products and to support your customer relationship with Cognex. Among other things, Cognex will utilize your information to alert you to product upgrades and updated product information or to send you other literature and/or information that you request. From time to time, Cognex may contact you via phone, email, or postal mail with information about various products and services. If you do not want to receive such communication, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. Or, at any time you can easily opt-out of receiving further marketing information from Cognex by contacting us via email at [contactus@cognex.com](mailto:contactus@cognex.com).

**How we use cookies and other methods for the collection of website usage data**

Some of our web pages utilize "cookies" so that we can better serve you with tailored information when you return to our site. Cookies are small files that our website may send to your browser and it is kept on your computer to make our website function properly, to provide business and marketing information to us and to facilitate your next visit to our site. The cookie data may improve form interactions based on information you have previously given to us. For example, in some cases, we will allow you to bypass a web form if a form cookie exists, or we may pre-fill a form with previously supplied contact information. In general, you can visit the Cognex website without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself, such as your name, phone number, postal code or email address. 

Our web server collects IP addresses to obtain certain aggregate information concerning the use of our website. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you’re surfing the web. We do not link IP addresses to any personally identifiable information. Therefore you can remain anonymous when you visit our website. Occasionally you may be asked to give us more specific information about yourself, such as when you download software, register for a seminar or other event, respond to a survey, enter a contest from our website, and register at the customer portal. Supplying such information to us is optional, but you may be unable to complete certain transactions without giving such information.

**Types and kinds of cookies**

There are four types of cookies: 

  * **Strictly necessary** \- Technically essential to the provision of our website. For example, some cookies are used to enable secure login to restricted areas. 
  * **Performance** \- Monitor and assess our website and its use. For example, recording visits to reveal how a website is used and which parts are most popular. 
  * **Functionality** \- Enable additional functionality to improve user experience. For example, recording settings for future visits so as to save users having to repeat making the same choices. 
  * **Advertising/targeting** \- Use an identification number to monitor personal preferences for the purposes of personalizing pages and gathering further information. For example, presenting adverts or promotions for products similar to those previously viewed or purchased.

There are two main kinds of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies are deleted from your computer when you close your browser, whereas persistent cookies remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach their expiry date. 

**Cookies on our website**

Cognex uses the services of the third party vendor **Google Analytics** to help us measure and analyze the effectiveness of our website and how visitors use www.cognex.com. To do this, we may use web beacons and cookies provided by this third party vendor. The type of information we collect includes the pages visited and navigation patterns, which helps us learn how visitors use our site, and what information is of the most interest to our customers and visitors to our website. Although the third party vendor logs the information coming from our site on our behalf, Cognex controls how that data may and may not be used. If you do not want to assist Cognex in improving our website, products, services, offers, and marketing strategy, you can "opt-out" of this web-site analysis tool by downloading and installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

Our site uses **ClickTale** to record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity as well as any text you type in this website. ClickTale does not collect personally identifiable information (PII) that you do not voluntarily enter in this website. ClickTale does not track your browsing habits across web sites which do not use ClickTale services. We are using the information collected by ClickTale service to improve our website, make it more user-friendly and monitor that it is performing correctly. You can choose to rel="noopener noreferrer" disable the Service at [http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html.](http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html)

Our rel="noopener noreferrer" site uses **Eloqua** rel="noopener noreferrer" part of the [Oracle Marketing Cloud](https://www.oracle.com/marketingcloud/products/cross-channel/marketing-to-businesses.html). This cookie is used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. Once consent is provided, through a form submission by the visitor, we can associate a visitor’s rel="noopener noreferrer" ID to individual rel="noopener noreferrer" characteristics and past rel="noopener noreferrer" behavior. See more at: [http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/privacy/marketing-cloud-data-cloud-privacy-policy/index.html ](http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/privacy/marketing-cloud-data-cloud-privacy-policy/index.html)

Cognex uses **Google AdWords Remarketing** to advertise online using text or image ads. Remarketing is a feature that lets us reach people who have previously visited our site, and show them relevant ads when they visit other sites. Google use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website. For this purpose third party advertising provider cookies rel="noopener noreferrer" are set when you visit rel="noopener noreferrer" our website. Users may rel="noopener noreferrer" opt out of Google's use of rel="noopener noreferrer" cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page ](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/)

Our website uses **Google Adwords Conversion Tracking** which uses cookies to help us determine how many people who clicked on our Google Ads end up contacting us through the website. This tracking cookie is set on your browser only when you click on a Google Ad and these cookies help us increase the website’s effectiveness for our visitors. rel="noopener noreferrer" These cookies expire rel="noopener noreferrer" within 30 days and do not rel="noopener noreferrer" contain information that rel="noopener noreferrer" can identify you personally. rel="noopener noreferrer" Please refer to the [Google Advertising Privacy Notice](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) for more information about Google Conversion Tracking and the ability to opt out.

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

**Manage cookies**

You can, if you wish, set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. If you wish to control or prevent the use of these cookies, please rel="noopener noreferrer" edit the settings of your rel="noopener noreferrer" web browser. For further information rel="noopener noreferrer" about how to refuse rel="noopener noreferrer" cookies, please refer rel="noopener noreferrer" to your browser “help” rel="noopener noreferrer" section or see [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

If Cognex decides to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

If you have any comments or questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at [legal@cognex.com](mailto:legal@cognex.com). We will address any issue to the best of our abilities.

### EU PRIVACY POLICY

**Cognex Global Applicant Privacy Notice (v. 22-Oct-2018)**

This policy lets you know how Cognex Corporation and its affiliates and subsidiaries ("Cognex" or "we") collect and use your personal information in connection with Cognex's recruiting efforts, both online and offline. Providing personal information in connection with the recruiting or job application process confirms your consent for Cognex to collect that information and to use, transfer, retain and share it with third parties as specified in this policy. 

Please click here to scroll to the policy for applicants who apply to work with Cognex hiring entities in the European Economic Area ("EEA"). 

**Voluntary Disclosure.**

Providing personal information in connection with recruiting is voluntary, and you determine the extent of information you provide to Cognex; please note that if you decide not to provide information, it may affect our ability to consider you for employment.

**Personal Information Collected.**

We collect information you choose to provide, such as your email or postal address, educational and employment background, contact information and preferences, job qualifications, and jobs for which you would like to submit an application, in order to contact you regarding our recruitment process and to evaluate your candidacy for a position. You also may choose to provide Cognex additional information, such as your CV, resume or transcripts; employment references and related information; and compensation information. In addition, Cognex may collect information from third parties, for example, in connection with a background or employment check and/or an employment reference. We collect non-personal information such as browser type, operating system, and web pages visited to help manage our websites. We use cookies and other internet technologies to manage our website and e-mail programs. We do not use these technologies to collect or store personal information.

**Sensitive Personal Information.**

Cognex does not request or require sensitive personal information concerning religion, health, sexual orientation, or political affiliation in connection with recruiting. If you have a disability and would like Cognex to consider any accommodation, you may provide that information during the recruiting process. In some countries, we also ask for information such as race or ethnicity for the purpose of monitoring equal opportunity; however, we do not require applicants to provide race or ethnicity information, and if you provide this information, it will not be view-able in the hiring or selection process. 

To the extent information you provide contains details of your racial or ethnic origin; political opinions or beliefs; religious beliefs; membership in a trade union or political party; physical or mental health or condition; sexual orientation; commission or alleged commission of an offense or related proceedings; job evaluations or educational records, you expressly authorize Cognex to handle such details as specified in this policy.

**Your Responsibilities.**

You are responsible for the information you provide or make available to Cognex. You must ensure that the information you submit is complete and true. Also, if you provide any information concerning any other person, such as individuals you provide as references, you are responsible for providing any notices and obtaining any consents necessary for Cognex to collect and use that information in a manner consistent with this policy.

**Use of Personal Information.**

Your information will be used for the following purposes:

  * Personal information is collected for Cognex's job application process and throughout the hiring process.
  * Cognex may use your personal information to contact you anytime during your candidacy for employment, to send you announcements, or request other types of information as required relating only to recruitment purposes.
  * Cognex may share your personal data with Cognex personnel in countries other than the country from which you are applying. Your information will be treated in accordance with the legal requirements of the country of submission.
  * Cognex will not trade, sell or otherwise transfer your personal information for use by any other companies.

**Data Recipients and Sharing with Third Parties.**

Cognex may share your personal information internally and with service providers and other third parties as necessary in connection with recruiting, employment, corporate governance, acquisitions, and legal or regulatory requirements. Cognex requires that its service providers and such other third parties keep your personal information confidential and that they only use the personal information in furtherance of the specific purpose for which it was disclosed. Cognex and its service providers may use your personal information in an anonymized format (in a form in which your identity cannot be determined) for other purposes not specified above.

**Security and Confidentiality.**

Except as otherwise stated in this policy or as required for legal or regulatory purposes, Cognex treats your personal information as confidential and will not disclose it to third parties without your consent. Cognex maintains, and requires its services providers to maintain, reasonable administrative, physical, and technical controls designed to protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information. Cognex employees who may have access to personal information are required to keep that information confidential.

Cognex may employ security procedures at its facilities and on its computer systems to monitor and maintain security, including the use of closed circuit television. Any monitoring of Cognex facilities, systems or assets is performed in accordance with applicable law.

**Retention and Access.**

Cognex may retain your information to consider you for other job opportunities. To the extent permitted or required by law, Cognex may delete data at any time; you should therefore retain your own copy of any information you submit to us.

You may access and correct personal information you have submitted by logging back into your account or contacting us by mail addressed to Cognex Corporation, One Vision Drive, Natick, MA 01760, USA, Attention: Chief Privacy Officer. 

**Your Rights & Choices.**

You have the right to have a copy of the personal information you provide, and to correct, update or modify your personal information. You may instruct Cognex to remove you from our programs by sending an email to hr.europe@cognex.com or by contacting us by mail addressed to Cognex Corporation, One Vision Drive, Natick, MA 01760, USA, Attention: Chief Privacy Officer. You may instruct Cognex to remove any previous consent you provided to share your personal information with other companies. 

**Dispute Resolution.**

Cognex is committed to working with candidates to obtain fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy. Cognex complies with country data protection laws. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with this policy or unresolved privacy or data use concerns, you should first contact us at hr.europe@cognex.com. We will investigate and attempt to resolve any such complaints or disputes. We cooperate with country data protection authorities if they believe a privacy problem has occurred. 

**Cross Border Transfers.**

Cognex is a global corporation with operations worldwide and has developed global data practices designed to assure your personally-identifiable information is appropriately protected. Please note that personal information may be transferred, accessed and stored globally as necessary for the uses and disclosures stated above in accordance with this policy. The Cognex affiliates have entered into and signed an Intra-Group Data Transfer Agreement for the international transfer of personal information within the Cognex Corporation Group which allows for the processing of your personal information in compliance with applicable local laws.

I AUTHORIZE COGNEX TO COLLECT, PROCESS, TRANSFER, AND USE MY PERSONAL DATA STORED IN A DATABASE LOCATED IN THE UNITED STATES OR OTHER COUNTRIES FOR PURPOSES OF THE APPLICATION AND HIRING PROCESS, FOR SENDING ANNOUNCEMENTS OF FUTURE JOB OPPORTUNITIES WITH COGNEX AS THEY BECOME AVAILABLE OR FOR ADMINISTRATION PURPOSES.

**Cognex Applicant Privacy Notice – Europe (v. 22-Oct-2018)**

**1\. Introduction**

This Applicant Privacy Notice (“ **Privacy Notice** ”) applies to the Personal Data (as defined below) collected about persons (“ **Applicant** (s)”, “ **you** ” or “ **your** ”) who apply to work with Cognex hiring entities in the EEA (“ **we** ” or “ **us** ” " **our** ”). For the purposes of this Privacy Notice, Personal Data is any information that relates to you or any other identified or identifiable persons. The controller of your Personal Data is the hiring entity indicated in the employment opportunity to which you are responding. 

This Privacy Notice describes the Personal Data we collect, how we collect it, why we collect Personal Data and the legal justifications for doing so, how long we keep Personal Data, with whom we share it and where, how we secure it, your rights and how to contact us. 

**2\. Personal Data about you that we collect and use**

We collect and use the following information about you where relevant to the position for which you are applying:

**Marketing (SMS & emails)**

  * contact information (such as name, address, email address, and phone number); 
  * experience information (such as education, skills, work experience and/or CVs, photograph, references, and employee records);
  * demographic information (such as age, date of birth, gender), disability status (where required); psychometric and ability test results; interview records; data from public profiles;

and Personal Data voluntarily provided by you. 

Where we have a legal obligation to do so, we also collect the following Special Categories of Personal Data: physical or mental fitness for the position for which you have applied. We only collect Special Categories of Personal Data as necessary to carry out an obligation we have under applicable law or when authorized by European Union or Member State law, providing appropriate safeguards for the rights and freedoms of Applicants. For the purposes of this Privacy Notice, “ **Special Categories of Personal Data** ” means Personal Data that reveals religious or philosophical beliefs or data concerning health.

**3\. The way we will collect your Personal Data**

Your Personal Data is collected in different ways, for example, data will most often be collected directly from you where you complete an application form, provide your CV, passport or other identity documents or through interviews and any other forms of assessment, such as online testing. 

On occasion, Personal Data may be provided to us by recruitment agents, former employers and other references that you provide, and, where permitted by law and depending on the role which you have applied for, employment background check providers and criminal records check providers. 

**4\. Purposes and Legal bases for using your Personal Data**

We collect and use your Personal Data for various purposes in connection with administration of the application process. Our processing of Personal Data is based on one or more legal justifications (sometimes called ‘legal bases’). The justifications for processing Personal Data and the purposes of that processing are as follows:

  * to take steps necessary to entering into an employment contract (or for Germany, necessary for hiring decisions), 
    * administering and managing your application;
    * assessing your skills, qualifications and your suitability for our career opportunities;
    * taking measures to verify that the information you have provided is true and accurate, e.g. by means of reference checks;
    * conducting background checks (which may include criminal background checks) as permissible and required for your role, except where your explicit consent is required (see below);
  * to comply with an EU legal obligation to which we are subject (applicable for Germany only where Personal Data is not processed for employment-related purposes), notably: 
    * conducting background checks (which may include criminal background checks) as permissible and required for your role, except where your explicit consent is required (see below);
    * dealing with legal disputes and establishing, exercising and defending (potential) legal claims;
    * complying with applicable EU or member state laws and regulations, such as anti-discrimination legislation;
  * to serve our legitimate interests, where your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests, notably: 
    * dealing with legal disputes and establishing, exercising and defending (potential) legal claims;
    * complying with other applicable laws and regulations, or relevant codes of conduct;

Our “ **legitimate interests** ,” are to hire qualified and appropriate people, to find the right candidate for future openings and to secure, defend and develop our business; (applicable for Germany only where Personal Data is not processed for employment related purposes);

  * where we have your free and explicit consent, notably: 
    * in some cases, making reference checks to verify that the information you have provided is true and accurate;
    * keeping your record for future hiring needs, including for the purpose of communicating with you and providing you with information regarding potential career opportunities that suit your profile;
    * in some cases, conducting background checks (which may include criminal background checks) as permissible and required for your role.

We require the Personal Data requested in the application process to assess your application for employment with us. We will tell you when we ask for Personal Data due to a contractual requirement or to comply with our legal obligations. If you do not provide some or all of this Personal Data, it may affect our ability to process your application and therefore to enter into an employment agreement with you. If you volunteer to provide the Personal Data to us, you may exercise your right to request that we limit the processing of your Personal Data at any time as set forth in the “Your Rights” section below. 

**5\. Retention of your Personal Data**

We will retain your Personal Data for as long as necessary for the purposes for which the Personal Data was collected and used by us, as stated in this Privacy Notice. In addition, we may retain your Personal Data in order to consider you for other job opportunities for up to 12 months, unless you request that we do not retain your Personal Data. 

If you accept employment with us, your Personal Data will be held on the basis set out in our Employee Privacy Notice. This will generally apply for the duration of your employment relationship with us plus any applicable statutory retention periods.

**6\. Disclosure and transfer of your Personal Data**

The data we collect will be stored in different systems and data bases, including on your application record, in HR files and on other IT systems (including email).

Your Personal Data will be shared for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice with members of our HR and recruitment team, interviewers involved in the recruitment process, managers in the business area with a vacancy and IT staff who need to access any of the Personal Data to perform their roles.

Where you provide us with details on former employers as referees, if your application for employment is successful, we will share your data with former employers to obtain references for you, with employment background check providers to obtain necessary background checks in relation to the specific role and to obtain criminal records checks where permissible and necessary for the role.

We may transfer your Personal Data outside the EEA to other Cognex entities and where our subcontractors or processors host data or process outside the EEA. If we do, we will ensure a similar degree of security of Personal Data by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is in place: 

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that the European Commission have approved as providing an adequate level of protection for personal data by; or
  * Where we share Personal Data among Cognex entities or where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts or codes of conduct or certification mechanisms approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe; or 
  * If we use US-based providers that are part of EU-US Privacy Shield, we may transfer data to them, as they have equivalent safeguards in place.

In those cases, you will have the right to ask us for more information about the safeguards we have put in place as mentioned above (e.g. to request a copy where the safeguard is documented, which may be redacted to ensure confidentiality), by contacting us as indicated in Section 9, “Contact us”.

**7\. Security**

We take reasonable steps to ensure that your Personal Data is properly secured using appropriate technical, physical, and organizational measures, so that it is protected against unauthorized or unlawful use, alteration, unauthorized access or disclosure, accidental or wrongful destruction, and loss. 

We take steps to limit access to your Personal Data to those persons who need to have access to it for one of the purposes listed in this Privacy Notice. Furthermore, we contractually ensure that any third party processing your Personal Data equally provides for the confidentiality, security and integrity of your Personal Data.

If you are successful in your application for employment, personal data gathered during the recruitment process will be transferred to your personal file and retained in accordance with our policies. You will be provided a new Employee Privacy Notice at that time. 

**8\. Your rights**

Subject to the conditions set forth in the applicable law, you may have the following rights with regard to our processing of your Personal Data:

Right to access, correct and delete your Personal Data - We are responsible for ensuring that all Personal Data that you give to us is accurately reflected in any systems where it is kept. You are responsible for ensuring that changes in personal circumstances (for example, change of address or bank account) are promptly notified to our Human Resources department, so that we can ensure that your Personal Data is up-to-date. 

You have the right to request access to any of your Personal Data that we may hold, and to request correction of any inaccurate Personal Data relating to you. You furthermore have the right to request deletion of any irrelevant Personal Data and to obtain a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you. You can request the deletion of your Personal Data, if (i) your Personal Data is no longer needed for the purposes of which it was collected, (ii) the sole legal basis for processing such data was your consent, and you have withdrawn such consent, (iii) you have objected to processing on the legal grounds relating to your particular situation, and we cannot prove that there are overriding legitimate grounds for processing, (iv) your Personal Data were processed unlawfully, or (v) your Personal Data must be erased in order to comply with legal requirements.

_Right to withdraw consent_ \- In the event your Personal Data is processed on the basis of your consent, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time by sending an email to privacy@cognex.com specifying your request, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

_Data portability_ \- To the extent that we use your Personal Data for performance of our employment contract with you and that Personal Data is processed by automated means, you have the right to receive all such Personal Data that you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another data controller where this is technically feasible.

_Right to restrict (limit) Personal Data use_ \- You have the right to restrict our use of your Personal Data where (i) you contest the accuracy of the Personal Data; (ii) the use is unlawful, but you do not want us to erase the Personal Data; (iii) we no longer need the Personal Data for the relevant purposes, but you require it for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; or (iv) you have objected to our Personal Data use justified on our legitimate interests pending verification as to whether we have compelling interests to continue the relevant Personal Data use.

**_Right to object_** \- To the extent that we are relying on our legitimate interests to use your Personal Data, you have the right to object to such use, and we must stop such processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the use that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the Personal Data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

_Lodge a complaint_ \- You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in your country of residence, if you consider that the collection and use of your Personal Data infringes this Privacy Notice or applicable law.

_Digital Legacy_ \- If you are an Applicant in France, you also have the right to issue directives relating to the disposition of your Personal Data after your death.

**Contact information**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our use of your Personal Data, or wish to inquire about or exercise any of your rights, please contact privacy@cognex.com. 

Alternatively, Applicants in Germany may always reach out to our data protection officer.
